

I am a research scientist of valeo.ai, a academic research lab focused on self-driving cars. My research interest is **machine learning** - **deep learning**, specifically the intersection of **natural language processing** and **computer vision** (zero-shot and few-shots learning, visual question answering, semantic retrieval, visual dialog...).

Employment

VALEO.AI October 2018–Present

Deep Learning Research Scientist

Academic research focused on self-driving car (semantic segmentation, object detection, few-shots learning...).

ONERA: The French Aerospace Lab

October 2015-September 2018

Deep Learning PhD student, supervisors: Dr.Stéphane Herbin and Pr.Frédéric Jurie
Combine vision and language for weakly supervised learning, zero-shot learning, image retrieval and visual reasoning.

ENSTA-ParisTech U2IS March 2015–August 2015

Robotics Research Trainee, supervisors: Dr.Mathieu Lefort and Pr.Alexander Gepperth Incremental learning of regularities in a multimodal data flow applied to developmental robotics.

Education

GREYC-CNRS October 2015–September 2018

Deep Learning PhD student, supervisors: Dr.Stéphane Herbin and Pr.Frédéric Jurie
Title: Learning and exploitation of semantic representations for image classification and retrieval

Paris-Sud university August 2015

Computer Science Research Master, Artificial Intelligence

Skills

Operating system: Unix systems

o Programming: Python, SQL

- o Python package: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Tensorflow, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn
- Language: French (Native), English (Full professional proficiency)

Publications

- o ADVENT: Adversarial Entropy Minimization for Domain Adaptation in Semantic Segmentation. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.
- Semantic bottleneck for computer vision tasks. In Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018.
- o Zero-Shot Classification by Generating Artificial Visual Features. In RFIAP, 2018.
- o Generating Visual Representations for Zero-Shot Classification. In International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) Workshops, 2017. (best paper award)
- o Improving Semantic Embedding Consistency by Metric Learning for Zero-Shot Classification. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2016.
- Hard Negative Mining for Metric Learning Based Zero-Shot Classification. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV)
 Workshops, 2016.